Guide to the Farnam Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- HENRY W. FARNAM (1853-1933), 1841-1941; Series II; 112 linear feet (222 boxes)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Europe, 1914 (Box 299, Folder 3603)
    - Examination papers, 1881-1895 (Box 299, Folder 3604)
    - Examination papers, 1895-1919 (Box 300, Folder 3605-3606)
    - Germany, 1876; 1897-1900 (Box 300, Folder 3607-3608)
    - Lowell House, 1901-1933 (Box 300, Folder 3609-3611)
    - New Haven Hospital and Connecticut Nurses Training School, 1919-1930 (Box 301, Folder 3612-3613)
    - Obituaries, 1830-1907 (Box 301, Folder 3614-3615)
    - Politics, 1880-1901 (Box 301, Folder 3616)
    - Politics, 1900-1928 (Box 302, Folder 3617-3620)
    - Travel, 1924 (Box 303, Folder 3621)
    - World War I
      - General, 1914-1919 (Box 303, Folder 3622-3624)
      - Relief appeals, 1917-1920 (Box 304, Folder 3625-3629)
      - Relief appeals, 1918-1923 (Box 305, Folder 3630-3632)
    - Yale University
      - General, 1869-1899 (Box 306, Folder 3633-3636)
      - General, 1898-1921 (Box 307, Folder 3637-3640)
      - General, 1916-1931 (Box 308, Folder 3641-3643)
      - Bicentennial, 1901 (Box 309, Folder 3644-3645)
      - Class of 1874, 1924 (Box 309, Folder 3646)
      - Yale Review, 1892-1912 (Box 309, Folder 3647)
    - Clippings: miscellanea, 1870-1892; 1913-1932 (Box 310, Folder 3648-3651)
- WILLIAM W. FARNAM (1844-1929), 1860-1929; Series III; 1 linear feet (2 boxes)
  This series is arranged in two sections: Correspondence and Topical files.
  Correspondence includes two sub-sections: "General," which is arranged chronologically, and "Select," which is arranged alphabetically.
  Topical files is arranged alphabetically.
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1860-1928, undated (Box 311, Folder 3552-3555)
    - Select
      - Dwight, Timothy, 1874 (Box 311, Folder 3556)
      - Farnam, Anna S., 1929 (Box 311, Folder 3557)
      - Farnam, Susan W., 1917 (Box 311, Folder 3558)
      - New Haven Park Commission, 1913; 1929 (Box 311, Folder 3559)
      - Roosevelt, Theodore: banquet, 1901 (Box 311, Folder 3560-3561)
      - Taft, William Howard, 1908-1928 (Box 311, Folder 3562)
      - Yale University
        - General, 1900-1914 (Box 311, Folder 3563)
        - Class of 1866, 1906; 1921 (Box 311, Folder 3564)
      - Yale Bicentennial, 1901 (Box 311, Folder 3565)
      - Woolsey, A. H., 1878 (Box 311, Folder 3566)
  - Topical files
    - Farnam, Susan W.: diary, 1866-1870 (Box 312, Folder 3567-3568)
    - Financial papers, 1894-1914 (Box 312, Folder 3569)
    - House, 1904-1908 (Box 312, Folder 3570-3571)
    - Real estate: Iowa, 1898-1926 (Box 312, Folder 3572)
    - Trusts, 1912-1919 (Box 312, Folder 3573)
    - World War I orphans, 1917-1927 (Box 312, Folder 3574-3575)
- OVERSIZE
  - Henry Farnam, 1853-1879 (Box 313)
  - Henry W. Farnam, 1892-1924 (Box 313)
  - William W. Farnam, 1871-1912 (Box 313)
- Addendum
  - Correspondence of Ann Sophia Whitman Farnam, 1903-1904 (Box 314, Folder 3576)
  - Unidentified letters & letter fragments, undated (Box 314, Folder 3577)
  - Unidentified photographs & memorabilia, 1914, undated (Box 314, Folder 3578)
- Additional material, 1803-2002; Accession 2004-M-028
  This addition to the Farnam Family Papers consists of two integrated accessions containing correspondence; diaries; financial and personal papers; and photographs of the Farnam and associated families. Whenever possible, the files have been maintained in the order in which they were received and original folder titles have been used. The correspondence contains both incoming and outgoing correspondence.
  - Correspondence
    - Kingsley, James Luce, 1828-1853 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Upham, George, 1831-1840, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Kingsley, William Lathrop to [Hannah?] Louise Upham, 1857, 1875-1883 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 4)
    - Kingsley, Hannah Louise Upham, 1857, 1861, 1874-1883 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Perit, Maria, to [Hannah?] Louise Kingsley, 1862, 1870-1885 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Kingsley, William Lathrop to Elizabeth Upham Kingsley Farnam, 1890-1891 (Box 1, Folder 7 - 11)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott [railroad accident], 1905 April (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott and Elizabeth Kingsley Farnam, 1899-1925 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Kingsley, James Luce, letterbook, 1828-1839 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Kingsley, William Lathrop, 1885-1890 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Kingsley, William Lathrop and Jeannie Taylor Kingsley, 1891-1894, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 16 - 17)
    - Farnam family [concerning Norwich], 1893, 1909, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Blake, Henry T. and Elizabeth Kingsley Blake, 1836-1857, 1886-1890, 1916-1919 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Upham, Timothy and Elizabeth Upham, 1803-1830, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott [trip to Hawaii, China, etc.; typescript], 1924 August 15-1925 January 3 (Box 2, Folder 21 - 22)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott, 1892-1893, 1904-1926 (Box 3, Folder 23 - 27)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott and Elizabeth Kingsley Farnam, 1901-1902 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott and Elizabeth Kingsley Farnam to Ann Sophia Whitman Farnam, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Farnam, Ann Sophia Whitman [includes correspondence from William Whitman Farnam abroad]
      - 1890-1892 (Box 3, Folder 30 - 38)
      - 1893-1898 (Box 4, Folder 39 - 55)
      - 1899-1903 (Box 5, Folder 56 - 64)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott [from economists, including Irving Fisher], 1900 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott and Arthur Hadley [concerning Landberg Collection of Semitic manuscripts], 1900 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott and Elizabeth Kingsley Farnam, 1899-1900 (Box 5, Folder 67 - 69)
    - Farnam, Ann Sophia to Henry Walcott Farnam [includes Hadley's first commencement], 1899-1900 (Box 5, Folder 70 - 71)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott and Elizabeth Kingsley Farnam to Ann Sophia Farnam [summer, Stockbridge], 1898 July-September (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - Farnam, Ann Sophia to Henry Walcott and Elizabeth Kingsley Farnam, 1890-1893 (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Farnam, Ann Sophia [predominantly from Henry Walcott Farnam], 1889 (Box 6, Folder 74 - 75)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott and Elizabeth Upham Kingsley, 1889-1890 (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - Farnam, Ann Sophia, 1888 (Box 6, Folder 77 - 79)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott [to parents and Sophia Bronson from Weimar, Halle, New Haven; includes typescripts], 1859-1875 (Box 6, Folder 80 - 88)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott and William Whitman Farnam, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 89)
    - Farnam, Ann Sophia to Sophia Bronson [includes typescript], 1845-1852 (Box 6, Folder 90 - 93)
    - Farnam, Ann Sophia and family to Henry Farnam, 1852-1858 (Box 7, Folder 94 - 99)
    - Farnam, Henry [includes family letters], 1851-1876 (Box 7, Folder 100 - 101)
    - Farnam, Henry to Ann Sophia Farnam, 1861-1865 (Box 7, Folder 102 - 103)
    - Farnam, Ann Sophia to Sophia Bronson [typescript], 1864-1868 (Box 7, Folder 104 - 114)
    - Farnam, Ann Sophia to William Whitman Farnam [includes typescript], 1866-1871 (Box 8, Folder 115 - 122)
    - Farnam, George Bronson [includes typescript], 1859-1867 (Box 8, Folder 123 - 130)
    - Farnam, Sarah Sheffield to Ann Sophia Farnam[includes typescript], 1859, 1872 (Box 8, Folder 131 - 133)
    - Farnam, Sarah Sheffield to Sophia Bronson [typescript], 1863 (Box 8, Folder 134)
    - Farnam, Henry [as presidential elector], 1872 (Box 8, Folder 135)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott [includes correspondence from Ann Sophia Farnam and Henry Farnam, concerning the name "Walcott" and railroads], 1875-1879 (Box 9, Folder 136 - 141)
    - Farnam, Ann Sophia, 1878, 1880, 1883-1887 (Box 9, Folder 142 - 151)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott [concerning Ann Sophia Farnam], 1904 (Box 9, Folder 152)
    - Farnam, Henry [concerning the railroad], 1851- 1859 (Box 9, Folder 153 - 159)
    - Farnam, Elizabeth Kingsley to Ann Sophia Farnam, 1890-1900 (Box 10, Folder 160)
    - Farnam, Elizabeth Kingsley to Henry Walcott Farnam and Ann Sophia Farnam [including correspondence from China], 1889-1913, 1924 (Box 10, Folder 161 - 166)
    - Farnam, Elizabeth Kingsley [Portsmouth], 1914 (Box 10, Folder 167)
    - Farnam, Louise Whitman [including photographs of Changsha], 1931-1933 (Box 10, Folder 168 - 176)
    - Farnam, Louise Whitman, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 177 - 179)
    - Kingsley, William Lathrop, 1857-1871, 1890 (Box 11, Folder 180)
    - Kingsley, Silliman, Upham, Webster [miscellaneous correspondence], 1839-1877 (Box 11, Folder 181)
    - Gilman, [William C.?], 1859, 1880, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 182)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott [includes address book and record of correspondents], 1875-1917 (Box 11, Folder 183 - 184)
    - Farnam, William Whitman and Susan Strong Farnam, 1899-1903, undated (Box 11, Folder 185)
    - Farnam, Elizabeth Kingsley and Henry Walcott Farnam [includes clippings], 1890-1891, undated (Box 11, Folder 186)
    - Farnam, Jeffrey A. to Henry Farnam, 1832-1841 (Box 11, Folder 187)
    - Wilson, Louise Whitman Farnam [war years, Wilson trust, and letters of condolence], 1940-1946, 1948-1949 (Box 11, Folder 188 - 191)
  - Diaries
    - Farnam, Elizabeth Upham Kingsley
      - 1865, 1872 Jul 19-1881 Jul 2 [4 vols.] (Box 12, Folder 192 - 195)
      - 1881 Aug 17-1887 Mar 31 [3 vols.] (Box 12, Folder 196 - 198)
      - 1887 Apr 1-1894 Dec 25 [5 vols.] (Box 13, Folder 199 - 203)
      - 1895 Jan 1-1921 Dec 31 [7 vols.] (Box 14, Folder 204 - 208)
      - 1922 Jan 1-1941 Dec 31 [4 vols.] (Box 15, Folder 209 - 210)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott
      - 1873 [1 vol., expedition with Othniel Charles Marsh] (Box 15, Folder 211)
      - 1890 Jul 20-1897 Sep 6 [9 vols., includes wedding trip diary] (Box 15, Folder 212 - 214)
      - 1897 Sep 7-1916 Apr 28 [24 vols.] (Box 16, Folder 215 - 222)
      - 1916 Apr 19-1933 Mar 16 [22 vols.] (Box 17, Folder 223 - 230)
      - Travel diaries [6 vols.], 1881, 1884-1886, 1889, 1909 (Box 17, Folder 231)
      - Student records [19 vols.], 1879 September-1899 June (Box 18, Folder 232 - 234)
    - Farnam, Jeffrey A. [2 vols.], 1827, 1832 (Box 18, Folder 235)
    - Farnam, Katharine Kingsley [2 vols.], 1907-1908 (Box 18, Folder 236)
    - Farnam, Susan Strong [4 vols.], 1866 March 30-1870 March 30, 1883 December 10-1884 February 18, [ca. 1888], 1906-1910 (Box 18, Folder 237)
    - Farnam, -- [1 vol.], 1858 (Box 18, Folder 238)
    - Kingsley, Louise Upham
      - 1859 Jan-1884 Jul [12 vols.] (Box 19, Folder 239 - 244)
      - Herbarium [1 vol.], 1838-1875 (Box 19, Folder 245)
      - Poetry journal [2 vols., poems transcribed by L. U. Kingsley], 1839-1855 (Box 19, Folder 246)
  - Financial papers
    - Farnam, Ann Sophia
      - Account books [includes charities], 1883-1904 (Box 20, Folder 247)
      - Alumni Hall [contract and papers relating to refinishing], 1881 (Box 20, Folder 248)
      - Cash book, 1901-1904 (Box 20, Folder 249)
      - Estate, 1904 (Box 20, Folder 250)
      - Memorandum concerning will, 1893 (Box 20, Folder 251)
    - Farnam, Henry
      - Account books [8 vols., includes charities], 1847-1848, 1862-1867, 1873-1883 (Box 20, Folder 252 - 254)
      - Bills, 1845-1852, 1854-1878 (Box 20, Folder 255 - 259)
      - Drafts and notes, 1840-1874 (Box 20, Folder 260)
      - Farmington Canal bills [includes payment to Jeffrey A. Farnam, Jr. for survey], 1834 (Box 21, Folder 261)
      - Inventory and income lists, 1864-1869 (Box 21, Folder 262)
      - Investments, 1838-1866 (Box 21, Folder 263)
      - New Haven & Northampton Railroad [treasurer order notes], 1836-1840 (Box 21, Folder 264)
      - Will and estate [includes correspondence], 1883-1905 (Box 21, Folder 265 - 272)
        General note
        See also: oversize, box 30
    - Farnam, Henry and Winthrop Hilyer, partnership papers [agreement and dissolution], 1836-1844 (Box 21, Folder 273)
    - Farnam, Henry Walcott, account books, 1867-1885 (Box 22, Folder 274)
    - Farnam, Jeffrey A., will and estate, 1837-1845 (Box 22, Folder 275 - 276)
    - Farnam, Sarah Sheffield, expenses [Paris], 1866-1869 (Box 22, Folder 277)
    - Farnam family, household account books and inventories, 1881-1936 (Box 22, Folder 278 - 279)
  - Personal papers
    - Awards, appointments and honors, 1892-1893 (Box 22, Folder 280)
    - Biographical sketches and memoirs, Farnam and associated families [manuscript and printed], 1911, undated (Box 22, Folder 281 - 283)
    - Biographical sketches and memoirs, Farnam and associated families [manuscript and printed], 1860-1933, undated (Box 23, Folder 284 - 291)
    - Biographical sketches and memoirs, Farnam and associated families [manuscript and printed], 1910, undated (Box 24, Folder 292)
    - Clippings [related to the railroad], 1863, 1875, 1905, 1931, 1948, undated (Box 24, Folder 293)
    - Genealogies, Farnam and associated families [manuscript and printed], 1845, 1889-1890, undated (Box 24, Folder 294 - 296)
    - Honorary and memorial publications, Farnam and associated families, 1873-1926 (Box 25, Folder 297 - 300)
    - Medical records, Henry Walcott Farnam [includes journal record of illness], 1926-1933 (Box 25, Folder 301)
    - Memorabilia [prints related to Yale College], undated (Box 25, Folder 302)
    - Miscellaneous documents, Henry Farnam, 1855-1858, [ca. 1883] (Box 25, Folder 303 - 304)
    - Passports, Henry Walcott Farnam and Ann Sophia Farnam, 1883, 1890 (Box 25, Folder 305)
    - Social clubs and events, 1831-1917, undated (Box 25, Folder 306 - 307)
    - Writings
      - Dana, Maria Trumbull, undated (Box 25, Folder 308)
      - Farnam, Ann Sophia [expository and poetry], undated (Box 25, Folder 309)
      - Farnam, Henry Walcott, 1884-1932 (Box 26, Folder 310)
      - Other authors, 1805, 1822, 1914-2002, undated (Box 26, Folder 311 - 315)
  - Photographs
    - Albums
      - Farnam, Henry Walcott
        - 1900-1906 [3 vols.] (Box 26, Folder 316)
        - 1907-1921, 1926-1928 [4 vols.] (Box 27, Folder 317)
      - Farnam and associated families [3 vols. and 2 daguerreotypes, portraits], undated (Box 28, Folder 318)
    - Loose photographs
      - Farnam, William Whitman and Susan Strong Whitman, 1919 Apr, undated (Box 29, Folder 319)
      - Farnam family, 1871-1955, undated (Box 29, Folder 320 - 325)
        See also: oversize 30
      - Whitman, Elizabeth Whiting [portrait, mother of Ann Sophia Whitman Farnam], undated (Box 29, Folder 326)
      - Wilson, Louise Farnam, 1923, 1931-1932 (Box 29, Folder 327)
  - Oversize
  - Financial papers, Henry Farnam, will and estate [correspondence], 1896-1901 (Box 30, Folder 328)
    - Photographs, loose photographs, Farnam family [Henry Walcott Farnam and Daniel Lathrop Coit, portraits], 1932, undated (Box 30, Folder 329)